A Guide to the Anson-Greene-Gravely Family Papers, 1832-1999
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Anson-Greene-Gravely Family Papers, 1832-1999
Library of Virginia
38550
12.85 cubic feet (31 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Nina Anson Gravely, 1 November 2001.
Biographical/Historical Information
Frederick Anson was born on 28 March 1811. He was made Canon to Queen Victoria in 1846. The year before he married Caroline Maria Vernon. She was born on 1 January 1826 and was the daughter of George John Warren, Fifth Lord Vernon, of Sudbury Hall. She died on 20 August 1918. Rev. William Anson died on 9 September 1885. They had 14 children.
Their son Alfred William Anson was born at Windsor on 24 June 1852. He emigrated to America at the age of 21, and settled in Augusta County, Virginia. In 1876 he married Georgina Frances Greene. She was born in 1851 and was the daughter of Rev. William Greene and Frances Whittle. They had come to America from Antrim, Ireland in 1872 and settled on their farm "Willowbrook" in Snyder, Augusta County. Alfred W. Anson also owned a farm near there. In 1890, Anson decided to enter the priesthood. He was ordained at St. John's Church in Richmond. After serving in Lynnhaven Parish in Princess Anne County, the family moved to Martinsville. Alfred W. Anson and his wife had six children. She died on 4 November 1892. Alfred W. Anson then remarried in 1894 to Mrs. Elena Moore Greene, the widow of his first wife's brother Augustus Newport Greene (1854-1890). She had three children from her previous marriage, and had two more daughters by Alfred Anson.
The children of Alfred W. Anson and Georgina Frances Green were: 1) Caroline Frances. She was born 15 March 1877. She married William H. Gravely (1864-1934). They had two children - William H., Jr. (1903- 1990) and Georgina Anson (b. 1905). Caroline Frances Gravely died on 29 December 1963. 2) Mary Ellen. She was born on 19 June 1880. She was married on 22 April 1903 to Thomas Granville Burch (1869-1951), a former mayor of Martinsville, member of the U.S. House of Representatives, and United States Senator. Mary Ellen Burch died on 7 January 1960. 3) Lucy Georgina. She was born on 24 June 1882. She never married, and died in March 1970. 4) Ethel Laura. She was born on 16 September 1884. She never married, and died in 1972. 5) Grace Evelyn. She was born in 1886. She married John Cary Jamison (1886-1959). 6) William Frederick Alfred. He graduated from the Virginia Military Institute in 1900 and was later a surveyor and engineer with the Virginia Department of Highways in Russell County. He married Vera Louise Seay on 14 October 1915. He died the following year on 19 July.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1832-1999, of the Anson, Greene, and Gravely families of Augusta, Henry, and Norfolk Counties, Virginia, and Georgia, Maryland, England and Ireland. The bulk of the collection covers the period 1900 to 1940. Includes correspondence, subject files, photographs, albums, scrapbooks, and publications. This collection was originally three accessions, but all have been filed together in Accession 38550.
Organization
Organized into the following four series: I. Dated Correspondence; II. Undated Correspondence; III. Subject Files; IV. Photographs, Albums, Scrapbooks, and Publications; V. Ledgers.
Contents List
- Correspondence (Dated) (Box 1-13)
  Most of the pre-1880 letters relate to the Greene family of Antrim, Ireland, and later Augusta County, Virginia, specifically Rev. William Greene (1807-1885) and his wife Frances Whittle (1816-1897). Subjects include legal matters, church issues, including a letter of appreciation from his congregation, as well as letters from their children which include family news, information on their travels, their health, and other routine matters.
  The Anson family letters appear around 1876 with a letter from Rev. Frederick Anson (1811-1885) to Rev. William Greene concerning the engagement of Alfred William Anson (1852-1923) to Georgina Frances Greene (1851-1892) and the couple's future financial situation. There is also a circular from Rev. Anson resigning his rectorship of Sudbury in 1877. After 1880, the Anson correspondence consists mainly of letters to and from Alfred W. Anson and his wife from their parents and other relatives, and other acquaintances in England and Ireland. The subject of the letters include family news, the family's farming activities in Augusta County, their health, as well as births, marriages, and deaths in the family and the area.
  The Gravely family letters begin to appear in the collection around 1880. Many of them are between William H. Gravely (1864-1934) and his father George Dyer Gravely (d. 1904) and concern Virginia politics and legal matters.
  The correspondence of the three families in the late 1800's focuses largely on the disposition of family property in Jamaica, England, and Ireland and the settlements of estates belonging to various family members. Also prominent in the letters are matters relating to the education of the Anson children, and Alfred W. Anson's decision to enter the priesthood. Their is a considerable amount of correspondence between his children and their grandmother Frances Whittle Greene and their aunt Jane Ellen Greene (1840-1931).
  In 1894, the Anson family moved to Martinsville, Virginia. Afterwards, the children made numerous visits to their relatives in England, and received much of their schooling there. There is a substantial amount of correspondence from them while crossing the Atlantic, as well as during their stay in England, with detailed descriptions of their encounters and family news.
  There is a large amount of information concerning World War I, and the opinions of the European citizenry, news of blackouts, and descriptions of territory taken by the German army as the war progressed. The letters between the World Wars deal mainly with family news, much of it concerning the deaths of various members. Also included is information on the education of William H. Gravely, Jr. (1903-1990) and his subsequent teaching career at Norfolk Academy, graduate work at the University of Virginia, and his resumption of teaching duties at the University of Maryland in College Park.
  The correspondence during World War II is mainly from Anson Jamison to his family while he was serving in Europe, North Africa, and Italy. The post-war correspondence, and especially the period after 1970, consists of letters mainly between William H. Gravely, Jr. and his sister Nina Anson Gravely (b. 1905).
  There is no Box 4 and 5.
  - 1842 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1862 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1865-1866 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1867 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1868 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1869 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1870 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1871 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1872 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1873 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1874 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1875 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1876 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1877 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1878 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1879 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1880 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1881 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1882 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1883 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1884 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1885 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1886 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1887 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1888 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1889 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1890 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1891 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1892 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1893 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1894 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1895 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1896 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1897 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1898 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1899 (January-October) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1899 (November) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1899 (December) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1900 (January 1-15) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1900 (January 16-31) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1900 (February 1-15) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1900 (February 16-28) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1900 (March) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1900 (April) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1900 (May-December) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1901 (January) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1901 (February) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1901 (March) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1901 (May) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1901 (June-July) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1901 (August-September) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1901 (October) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1901 (November 1-24) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1901 (November 25-30) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1901 (December) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1902 (January) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1902 (February) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1902 (March 1-6)) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1902 (MArch 7-15) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1902 (March 16-31) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1902 (April-June) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1902 (July 1-15) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1902 (July 16-31) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1902 (August) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 1902 (September) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1902 (October) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 1902 (Movember) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 1902 (December) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 1903 (January) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 1903 (February) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 1903 (March) (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 1903 (April) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 1903 (May) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 1903 (June) (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 1903 (August-October) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1903 (November) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1903 (December) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1904 (January-July) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1904 (August-December) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1905 (January-June) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1905 (July-December) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1906 (January-June) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1906 (July-September) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1906 (October 1-15) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1906 (October 16-31) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1906 (November-December) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1907 (January-June) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1907 (July-December) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1908 (January-April) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1908 (May-August) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1908 (September-December) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1909 (January-June) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1909 (July-October) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1909 (November-December) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1910 (January-April) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1910 (May) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1910 (June) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1910 (July) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1910 (August-October) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1910 (November-December) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1911 (January-May) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1911 (June) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1911 (July) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 1911 (August) (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 1911 (September) (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1911 (October) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 1911 (November-December) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 1912 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1913 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1914 (Box-folder Box 3, Folders 36-37)
    - January-June (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - July-December (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 1915 (Box-folder Box 3, Folders 38-39)
    - January-June (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - July-December (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - 1916 (Box-folder Box 6, Folders 1-3)
    - January-May (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - June-July (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - August-December (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1917 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1918 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1919 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1920 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1921 (Box Box 6, Folders 8-9)
    - January-June (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - July-December (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1922 (Box-folder Box 6, Folders 10-11)
    - January-June (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - July-December (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1923 (Box-folder Box 6, Folders 12-13)
    - January-May (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - June-December (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1924 (Box-folder Box 7, Folders 1-8)
    - January-March (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - April-July (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - August 1-20 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - August 21-31 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - September 1-15 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - September 16-30 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - October (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - November-December (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1925 (Box-folder Box 7, Folders 9-10)
    - January-May (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - June-December (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1926 (Box-folder Box 8, Folders 1-2)
    - January-June (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - July-December (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1927 (Box-folder Box 8, Folders 3-4)
    - January-June (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - July-December (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1928 (Box-folder Box 8, Folders 5-7)
    - January-April (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - May-June (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - July-December (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1929 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 9-Box 9, Folder 3)
    - January (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - February (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - March-April (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - May-June (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - July-September (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - October-December (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1930 (Box-folder Box 9, Folders 4-7)
    - January (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - February-March (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - April-June (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - July-December (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1931 (Box-folder Box 9, Folders 8-9)
    - January-April (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - May-December (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1932 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1933 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1934 (Box-folder Box 10, Folders 2-4)
    - January-March (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - April (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - May-December (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1935 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1936 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1937 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1938 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 8-11)
    - January-June (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - July (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - August-September (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - October-December (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 1939 (Box-folder Box 11, Folders 1-6)
    - January-February (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - March (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - April-May (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - June (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - July-September (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - October-December (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1942 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1943 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1944 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1945-1949 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1960-1963 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1965-1969 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1985-1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1990-1995 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1996-1999 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Correspondence (Undated) (Box 14-15)
  See description of Series I.
  - Anson, Alfred William (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Anson, Caroline Maria Vernon (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Anson, Elena More Greene (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Anson, Ethel Laura (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Anson, Georgina Frances (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Anson, Laura & Adelaide (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Anson, Lucy Georgina (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Anson, Vera Louise Seay (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Anson, William Frederick Alfred (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Barr, Francis Anson (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Burch, Mary Ellen Anson (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Clarke, Grace (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Gravely, Caroline Frances (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Gravely, Elizabeth Nisbet (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Gravely, Mary Hughes (Mollie) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Gravely, Minnie Walker Gregory (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Gravely, William Henry (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Gravely, William Henry, Jr. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Greene, Cloe (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Greene, Frances Whittle (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Greene, Francis H. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Greene, James Latimer (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Greene, Jane Ellen (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Greene, Julia Ellen (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Greene, Reginald Latimer (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Greene, Rev. William (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Jamison, Anson (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Jamison, Grace Evelyn Anson (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Jamison, John Cary (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Winston, Cornelia (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Incomplete and Unidentified (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
- Subject Files (Box 16-20)
  The subject files include recollections of Alfred William Anson and his wife, as well as their homes at Sudbury and Windsor, written by their daughter Laura Anson. Other items of note include information on the appointment of Rev. William Greene as Vicar of Antrim (1832), and an autograph book of William Gravely while he was attending the University of Virginia (1884). Also included in the subject files are clippings, information on various cruise lines, drawings, sketches, and paintings, genealogical notes on the Anson, Gravely, Greene, Harcourt, and Vernon families, greeting cards, and postcards. There are also numerous invitations to commencements, receptions, weddings, as well as to The White House and Windsor Castle. Also included is a Norfolk Academy catalogue (1926-27), obituaries, poetry, prayers, and hymns, speeches, sympathy cards, published works, and copies of the wills of George D. Gravely and Joseph Greene.
  - Accounts and Receipts (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Anson, Laura (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 2-4)
    - In Memory of Our Dear Parents - Additional Recollections (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Our First Home, Derbyshire (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Part III: Recollections - Our Windsor Home (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Appointment of Rev. William Greene as Vicar of Antrim, 1832 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Autograph Book of William H. Gravely - University of Virginia, 1884 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Autographs (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Bond (copy), 1933 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Bookmarks (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Bookplates (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Calendars (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Calling Cards (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Certificate of Election, 1903 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Certificates (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Clippings (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
  - Color Views of the Holy Land (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Cruise Lines Information (Box 16, Folder 18-19)
  - Democratic National Convention, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Danville & Western Railway Pass, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Deeds (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Diploma - Nina Anson Gravely, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Drawings, Sketches, and Paintings (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Dresbach, Glen Ward (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Envelopes (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Estate of Adelaide Mary Anson (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Estate of George L. Gravely (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Fee Book of Thomas L. Ranson (copy), 1877-1886 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Galt v. French et als. (Norfolk City Chancery Court, 1950) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Genealogical Notes (Box-folder Box 17, Folders 7-12)
    - Anson (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Gravely (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Greene (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Harcourt (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Vernon (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Guide Books and Brochures (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Greeting Cards and Postcards (Box-folder Box 17, Folders 14-17-Box 18, Folders 1-2)
    - Blank (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - Holiday, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
    - Holiday, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Hair (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Hotel Information (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - In Memory of Caroline Maria Anson, 1826-1918 by Harold Anson (1918) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Inauguration (Roosevelt), 1937 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Invitations (Box-folder Box 18, Folders 7-14)
    - Commencements, Receptions, etc. (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
    - Governor (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - The White House (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Wedding (Box 18, Folder 11-13)
    - Windsor Castle (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - List of Wedding Presents - Gravely/Anson, 1902 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Marriage Announcements (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Membership Cards (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Membership Certificate - Phi Kappa Phi, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Menus (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 5-9)
  - Norfolk Academy Catalogue, 1926-1927 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Poe, Edgar Allen (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Poetry, Prayers, and Hymns (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Prints (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Programs (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Russell County Bulletin, vol. 1, February, 1916 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Sams, Conway W. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Speeches (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Subpoena, 1902 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - State Normal School for Women (Farmville) (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Sympathy Cards (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - The Circle of Omicron Delta Kappa (vol. IX, no. 1), June, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - The Deserted Village by Oliver Goldsmith (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - The Palace and Abbey of Holyrood by Robert McBean (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Train Schedules (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - University of Virginia - Graduate Studies Dept. Handbook (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Will of George D. Gravely (copies) (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Will of Joseph Greene (copy) (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Photographs, Albums, Scrapbooks, and Publications (Box 21-31)
  The series of photographs, albums, scrapbooks, and publications contain various categories of photographs - identified and unidentified individuals, buildings, and groups. There are also negatives, and a number of family photo albums. Most of the photographs in the albums have been identified. Also included in this series are oversize photographs, a scrapbook, published books by members of the Anson family, miscellaneous magazines, and guidebooks.
  - Anson, Adelaide (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Anson, Alfred William (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Anson, Arthur (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Anson, Caroline Maria Vernon (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Anson, Charles Eustace (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Anson, Edith Vernon (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Anson, Ethel Laura (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Anson, Frederick (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Anson, Frederick Henry (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Anson, Georgina Francis Greene (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Anson, Hilda Vernon (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Anson, Hugh Richard (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Anson, Laura Ethel (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Anson, Lucy Georgina (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Anson, Walter Vernon (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Anson, William Frederick Alfred (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Burch, Mary Ellen Anson (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Burch, Thomas Granville (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Dora Road, Pulaski County, Virginia (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Gravely, Caroline Frances Anson (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Gravely, George Lewis (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Gravely, Georgina Anson (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Gravely, William Henry (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Gravely, William Henry, Jr. (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
  - Greene, Elizabeth Newport (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Greene, Jane Ellen (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Greene, Mary (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Greene, Reginald Latimer (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Greene, Urith Mary Newport (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Greene, William (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Greene, William Hastings (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Jamison, Alfred Anson (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Jamison, Grace Evelyn Anson (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Jamison, John Cary (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Jamison, Paul (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Sams, Conway Whittle (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Taylor, Mary Newport Greene (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Vernon, George Warren Venable (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Vernon, William Warren (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Whittle, Dennis (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Whittle, Henry Deering (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Photographs (Box-folder Box 23, Folders 2-7-Box 24, Folders 1-3)
    - Buildings (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Group (Box 23, Folder 2-4)
    - Misc. Individuals (Box 23, Folder 5-7)
    - Misc. Individuals (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
  - Negatives (Box 24, Folder 4-6)
  - Photo Album of Grace Anson Jamison (photocopy and original photographs) (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Family Photo Albums (Box 25-28)
  - Oversized Family Photographs and Scrapbook (Box 29)
  - Oversized Family Photographs and Published Books (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous Magazines and Guide Books (Box 31)
- Ledgers, 5 volumes.